Guide to the Isaac Thomas Littleton Papers
Isaac Thomas Littleton Papers
1953, 1958-1989
1953 1989
Littleton I. T. Isaac Thomas 1921-
MC 00185
The Isaac Thomas Littleton Papers contains the 1968 doctoral dissertation of Littleton, titled The Bibliographic Organization and Use of the Literature of Agricultural Economics, from the library science program at the University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign and a letter, 1968, to Littleton from Rolland E. Stevens, professor of library science at the University of Illinois, regarding the publication of a shorter version of the monograph. This collection also contains personal correspondence, speeches, copies of photographs, historical information on North Carolina State Universities Library and aricle drafts. Finally, there are the following items regarding his retirement in 1987, greeting cards, correspondence, newspaper clippings, a guestbook, cassette tapes, and other related items.
Isaac Thomas Littleton (1921- ) received an A.B. from the University of North Carolina in 1943, an M.A. from the University of Tennessee in 1950, and M.S. and Ph.D. in library science from the University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign in 1951 and 1968. He came to the D. H. Hill Library at the North Carolina State College of Agriculture and Engineering (later North Carolina State University) in 1959, as head of technical services and assistant director of libraries. Appointed acting director in 1964, Littleton succeeded Harlan Craig Brown as director of libraries in 1967, and retired in 1987.
1.5 linear feet
North Carolina State University Libraries, Special Collections Research Center
Gift of Isaac Thomas Littleton, 1987 July 21 (Accession no. 1987-0011), 2012 May (Accession no. 2012-0123), 2012 June (Accession no. 2012-0147).
This collection is arranged by type of material.
Isaac Thomas Littleton (1921- ) received an A.B. from the University of North Carolina in 1943, an M.A. from the University of Tennessee in 1950, and M.S. and Ph.D. in library science from the University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign in 1951 and 1968. He came to the D. H. Hill Library at the North Carolina State College of Agriculture and Engineering (later North Carolina State University) in 1959, as head of technical services and assistant director of libraries. Appointed acting director in 1964, Littleton succeeded Harlan Craig Brown as director of libraries in 1967, and retired in 1987.
Under Littleton's leadership, the D. H. Hill Library's collections increased dramatically, along with its physical space. During his tenure, the library became part of the Online Computer Library Center, the Southeastern Library Network, the Triangle Research Libraries Network, and the Association of Research Libraries. A member of several professional and honorary societies, Littleton was chairman of the University of North Carolina system's University Library Advisory Council, the Association of Southeastern Research Libraries, and the Southeastern Library Network.
The Isaac Thomas Littleton Papers contains the 1968 doctoral dissertation of Littleton, assistant director and director of libraries at the North Carolina State College of Agriculture and Engineering (later North Carolina State University) from 1959 to 1987. Titled The Bibliographic Organization and Use of the Literature of Agricultural Economics, the thesis was written towards Littleton's Ph.D. in library science from the University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign. This collection also contains a 1968 letter to Littleton from Rolland E. Stevens, professor of library science at the University of Illinois, regarding the publication of a shorter version of the monograph. Finally, there are the following items regarding his retirement in 1987, greeting cards, correspondence, newspaper clippings, a guestbook, cassette tapes, and other related items.
Littleton I. T. Isaac Thomas 1921-; Littleton I. T. Isaac Thomas 1921-; North Carolina State University--Faculty--History; North Carolina Librarians; United States Library science; Methodology Agriculture Economic aspects Bibliography; Agriculture Economic aspects Abstracting and indexing; Theses
- Thesis and Letter (Box 1)
  - Thesis:"The Bibliographic Organization and Use of the Literature of Agricultural Economics," (1 of 4), 1968 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Thesis:"The Bibliographic Organization and Use of the Literature of Agricultural Economics," (2 of 4), 1968 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Thesis:"The Bibliographic Organization and Use of the Literature of Agricultural Economics," (3 of 4), 1968 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Thesis:"The Bibliographic Organization and Use of the Literature of Agricultural Economics," (4 of 4), 1968 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Letter, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Retirement, 1987
  - Balloon, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Cards (1 of 3), 1987 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Cards (2 of 3), 1987 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Cards (3 of 3), 1987 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Cooperative Academic Library Networks: a forum in honor of I. T. Littleton (Cassette 1), 1987 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Cooperative Academic Library Networks: a forum in honor of I. T. Littleton (Cassette 2), 1987 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Dinner Honoring I. T. Littleton's Retirement, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Guest Book, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Memoranda, Correspondence and Bulletins, 1987 (Halfbox 3, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous Retirement Items, 1964, 1987 (Halfbox 3, Folder 2)
  - News Paper Clippings, 1987 (Halfbox 3, Folder 3)
- Personal Material
  - Correspondence (1 of 2), 1964-1974 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence (2 of 2), 1964-1974 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Professional Material
  - Correspondence and Articles, 1972-1989 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - History of North Carolina State Libraries, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Speeches (2 of 2), 1967-1978 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Speeches (1 of 2), 1968-1978 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Photograph Copies, 1955-1958 (Box 4, Folder 5)